Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Rockingham, NC, Yadkin River Power Company Storefront c. 1915-1920. Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company Local Office in Rockingham, NC. Lighting and other products can be seen displayed in the windows. Rockingham, Richmond County, NC c. 1915-1920, PhC.68.1.68; Carolina Power and Light
- Southport, NC, Aerial View c. 1974. Two identical aerial views (one color) of the city of Southport, NC and adjacent marina. Southport, Brunswick County, North Carolina c. 1974, PhC.68.1.69; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Yadkin River Power Company Storefront c.1912. Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company Local Office in Wadesboro, NC shown at night. Lighting products can be seen displayed in the windows. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC c. 1912, PhC.68.1.70.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Yadkin River Power Co Storefront c. 1917. Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company Local Office in Wadesboro, NC. Lighting and other products can be seen displayed in the windows. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC c. 1917, PhC.68.1.71; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Anson County Courthouse c. 1911. Street scene in Wadesboro, NC. Some of the original Anson county courthouse is seen. C.S. Wheeler Harness Shop is seen on the opposite side of the street. A horse and carriage is seen on the unpaved street. c. 1911, PhC.68.1.72; Carolina Power and Light
- Hamlet, NC, Main Street Business District c. 1923. Main Street in Hamlet, NC is seen looking west. Cars are seen lining the street as a pedestrian walks toward camera. Various business are also seen. Hamlet, Richmond County, NC c. 1923, PhC.68.1.73; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Bland Studio/ Yadkin River Power Company Storefront c.1916. Storefront of the Yadkin River Power Company Local Office in Wadesboro, NC at 117 North Greene Street. Lighting and other products can be seen displayed in the windows. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC c. 1916, PhC.68.1.74; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Intersection of Wade and Green Streets c. 1923. Pictured is the intersection of Green and Wade Streets looking northwest in Wadesboro, cars, people and businesses are seen. Taken from vantage point of Wheeler Harness Shop. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC 23 October 1923, PhC.68.1.75.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro, NC, Anson County Courthouse c. 1923. Exterior view of the Anson County Courthouse and surrounding grounds. Wadesboro, Anson County, NC c. 1923, PhC.68.1.76; Carolina Power and Light
- Wilmington, NC, Color Waterfront View c. 1974. Color view of waterfront in Wilmington, NC. New Hanover County, NC c. 1974, PhC.68.1.77; Carolina Power and Light
- Wilmington, NC, Wrightsville Beach Causeway Opening c. 1926. Dedication ceremony for the Wilmington-Wrightsville Beach Causeway June 1926. Ribbons are seen tied across the bridge with a decorated car just behind the ribbons. A marching band and a crowd are seen in the background. Wilmington, New Hanover County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.78; Carolina Power and Light
- Wilmington, NC, Wrightsville Beach Causeway c.1930. View of the Wilmington-Wrightsville Beach Causeway. Wilmington, New Hanover County, NC c. 1930., PhC.68.1.79.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Wilmington, NC, Bellmead Woods Plantation House c. 1930. Two views of the Bell Mead Woods plantation house located five miles from Wrightsville Beach. Print has a thorough historical details concerning the house pasted on the back. Wilmington, New Hanover County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.80.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Wrightsville Beach, NC, Tourists Gathered Lumina Pavilion c.1912. Two views of the Lumina Pavilion depicting formally dressed tourists gathering on the steps to the building. Wrightsville Beach, New Hanover County, NC c. 1912, PhC.68.1.81.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Zebulon, NC, Carolina Power and Light Office c. 1932. One front exterior view of the Zebulon Carolina Power and Light Office in Zebulon, NC and four interior views of the store and its merchandise. Small appliances and other electrical related goods are seen. c. 1932, PhC.68.1.82.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Zebulon, NC, Public Officials at Rural Fire Department c.1957. (left to right) Ed Hales, Dr. L. M. Massey, Dewey Massey, M. L. Hagwood, Horace Gay, Chief Willie B. Hopkins, Robert Ed Horton, and Grady Miller are seen posing next to a Zebulon fire engine. c. 1957, PhC.68.1.83; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified Courthouse c. 1923. Exterior view of an unidentified courthouse. c. 1923, PhC.68.1.84; Carolina Power and Light
- Goldsboro, NC, Interior/Front Exterior Carolina Theater c.1930. Two interior and one exterior view of the Carolina Theatre in Goldsboro, NC. Front exterior view also shows Opera House to the right of the theatre. Goldsboro, Wayne County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.85.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Henderson, NC, View of Garnet Street looking North c. 1935. View of Garnet Street looking north. First United Methodist Church can be seen on the left. Other stores and service stations can also be seen. Henderson, Vance County, NC c. 1935, PhC.68.1.86; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1909. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1909, PhC.68.1.87; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.88; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.89.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.90; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.91; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.92; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1916. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1916, PhC.68.1.93.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, East Side of Fayetteville Street c. 1915. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. A banner is seen hanging across Martin Street advertising for the State Fair. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC October 1929, PhC.68.1.94; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street During State Fair c. 1926. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. A banner is seen hanging across Martin Street advertising for the State Fair. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC October 1926, PhC.68.1.95; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View, Fayetteville Street c. 1943. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.96; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street, Spring 1940. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from the top of the NC Capitol dome. Street cars, pedestrians and businesses are seen running the length of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC, Spring 1940, PhC.68.1.97; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Streetcars at Fayetteville and Martin Streets, 15 May 1909. Street scene looking northeast at the intersection of Martin and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC. Three streetcars are seen stopped as the conductors pose for a picture. Citizens National Bank is seen on the northeastern corner of Fayetteville Street in the near background. An advertisement for the day's baseball game is seen on the front of the streetcar. 15 May 1909, PhC.68.1.98.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, US Post Office on Fayetteville Street, 15 May 1909. Street scene looking southwest at the intersection of Martin and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC. The Federal Building/Post Office/Century Station building is seen on the corner. To its immediate left is seen the Wake County Courthouse. Three horse and carriages can be seen parked in front of the post office. Streetcar lines and streets paved in Belgian block are clearly seen. 15 May 1909, PhC.68.1.99; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View of Fayetteville and Martin Streets c. 1913. Elevated view of Fayetteville and Wilmington Streets looking north in Raleigh, NC taken from the roof of the Commercial National Bank on Martin Street. Many downtown buildings can be seen including Raleigh Bank and Trust, the back of Citizens National Bank, NC Capitol, Ruffin Building, etc. Cars and horse and carriages can be seen on Wilmington Street near City Market. Raleigh, Wake County, North Carolina c. 1913, PhC.68.1.100.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, New Street Lamps on Fayetteville Street 6 February 1917. Street level view of Fayetteville Street looking north at the intersection of Davie. City Hall and Auditorium can be seen in the near background at the corner of Davie and Fayetteville Streets. Streetlights, pedestrians, shops, automobiles and horse and carriages are seen lining Fayetteville street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 6 February 1917, PhC.68.1.101; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Post Office/Wake County Courthouse Fayetteville Street, 6 February 1917. View of Fayetteville Street looking north northwest from Davie Street. In foreground is a newly installed luminous arc lamp. Wake County courthouse, Federal Building/Post Office and other buildings can be seen. Both automobiles and horse and carriages are seen along Fayetteville Street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 6 February 1917, PhC.68.1.102.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville St. from Morgan St., Raleigh, N.C., 1917. View looking south down Fayetteville Street from Capitol Square in Raleigh, NC. Automobiles, carriages, and pedestrians are seen lining the street. Streetcar rails are easily seen down the middle of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1917, PhC.68.1.103.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Corner of Davie and Fayetteville Streets c. 1910. Corner of Davie and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC is seen looking east down Davie Street. In addition to power poles and lines a corner grocery store, Henry G. Deboy, is seen. A horse and carriage bearing the stores name is seen parked just outside. Two bicycles are also seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.104; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking Toward Capitol c. 1923. 200 block of Fayetteville Street looking north toward State Capitol building. Automobiles, pedestrians and businesses can be seen lining the street with the capitol building in the background. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1923, PhC.68.1.105; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking North From Yarborough Hotel c. 1925. Fayetteville Street looking north from 300 block. The Yarborough Hotel can be seen on right side of street. Automobiles, pedestrians, and streetcars can be seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1925, PhC.68.1.106.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, West Side of Fayetteville Street Looking South c. 1926. West side of Fayetteville Street looking south down sidewalk from Morgan Street. Automobiles and pedestrians are seen lining the street. Signs for various businesses are also seen along with a newly installed D.C. Magnetite Arc Lamp. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.107; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, West Side of Fayetteville Street c. 1921. West side of Fayetteville Street looking south from Morgan Street. Pool and Crocker Shoe Store, Ellington's Photographic Studio, Johnson and Broughton, Hotel Giersch, Raleigh Banking and Trust and other unidentified businesses can be seen. A horse and carriage, parked cars and pedestrians are also seen. c.1921, PhC.68.1.108.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking South West Side Sidewalk c. 1924. Fayetteville Street looking south down west sidewalk. Pedestrians can be seen walking away from camera. Parked automobiles and streetlights are seen lining the streets. c. 1924, PhC.68.1.109.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, East Side of Fayetteville Street Looking South c. 1945. East side of Fayetteville Street looking south from the Hargett Street. The Haywood Building, Royster's, Charles Stores Company, Wake Theater and other businesses are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1945, PhC.68.1.110; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking North From Hotel Sir Walter c. 1947. Fayetteville Street looking north from Hotel Sir Walter at Davie Street. Cars, pedestrians and various businesses can be seen including City Hall and Municipal Building and Durham Life Insurance Building. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1947, PhC.68.1.111; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Lightner Hotel and Arcade 122 East Hargett Street c. 1926. View looking east down Hargett Street Lightner Hotel and Arcade and the Montague Building are seen on the right. Automobiles are seen lining the street as African Americans are seen standing on sidewalk. Fire Station #3 can be seen on extreme left in background at the corner of Hargett and Blount Streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.112.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Lightner Hotel and Arcade 122 East Hargett Street c. 1926. View looking east down Hargett Street Lightner Hotel and Arcade and the Montague Building are seen on the right. Automobiles are seen lining the street as African Americans are seen standing on sidewalk. A sign for Raleigh Auction Company can also be seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.113.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, East Hargett Street Business District c. 1943. East Hargett Street looking east across Wilmington Street in Raleigh, NC. Moderate traffic is seen on the roads. Pedestrians are seen on sidewalks passing various businesses. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.114.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Hargett Street Business District, Raleigh, N.C., 1943. Intersection of Hargett and Wilmington Streets looking west. Scene is busy with cars, bicycles and pedestrians. Local businesses are seen including Goodmans Millinery, G & S Department Store, Johnson Jewelers, Pizer Prose Ladies and Men's Ready to Wear, Fines Men's Store, Radio-Camera Supply and Capitol Cigar Store. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.115.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Southwestern Corner of Hargett and Fayetteville Streets, Raleigh Building c. 1947. Pictured is the Raleigh Building on the southeastern corner of Hargett and Fayetteville streets in Raleigh, NC. Businesses including Walgreens Drugs, Bowman's Jewelers, and McLeod and Watson Clothing are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1947, PhC.68.1.116; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, View of NC Capitol from Hillsborough Street c.1909. View of NC Capitol and Confederate Monument looking west from Hillsborough Street in Raleigh, NC. Pedestrians, streetcars, streetcar tracks and lines are all seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC. c. 1909, PhC.68.1.117; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View of Hillsborough Street From NC Capitol Dome c. 1909. Elevated view of Hillsborough Street from the NC Capitol Dome. Raney House is seen on the Corner of Hillsborough and Salisbury as well as the Confederate Monument on the Capitol grounds. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1909, PhC.68.1.118; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View of Martin Street Looking West c. 1908. Elevated view of Martin Street in Raleigh, NC looking west from the top of Commercial National Bank. Citizen's National Bank is seen in foreground on right. Below, carriages, automobiles, streetcars and pedestrians are all seen in the streets. On far left the 1912 construction/expansion project of Century Post Office can be seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1912, PhC.68.1.119.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Martin Street Looking West c. 1912. West Martin Street looking west from 100 block. The two-and-a-half story brick building on the extreme right is the News and Observer building. The paper moved here from Fayetteville St about 1908. Part of the Academy Building is seen on extreme left. Hotel Raleigh is seen on right at intersection with McDowell Street. Martin Street appears to be decorated for a parade, possibly President Tafts visit to Raleigh. Raleigh, Wake County, NC, PhC.68.1.120.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Martin Street Looking East c. 1917. Martin Street in Raleigh, North Carolina looking east. Various businesses are seen including, The Strand Hotel, Dillon Supply Company, Thompson Electric, Hotel Wright, and Circle Pharmacy. Automobiles and bicycles are seen parked along the side of the street as streetcar rails run down the center. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1917, PhC.68.1.121.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View Martin Street c. 1919. Elevated view of Martin Street in Raleigh, NC looking west from the top of Commercial National Bank. Day and night views. Various downtown buildings are seen including, Capital Club building, The Bland Hotel, and Century Post Office. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 1919, PhC.68.1.122.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Martin Street Looking East c. 1946. 100 Block of Martin Street in Raleigh, NC. Various businesses are seen in the buildings along the street including, Andrew Johnson Hotel, Wachovia Bank and Trust, Bob's Grill, The Maple Club, Hotel Raleigh Annex, and Palace Theater. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1946, PhC.68.1.123; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Salisbury Street Looking North c. 1943. 300 block of Salisbury Street looking north in Raleigh, NC. Automobiles are seen parked and traveling down the busy street. Various buildings are seen including, Capital Club Building, Century Post Office, Lawyer's Building and Andrew Johnson Hotel. State Theatre can be seen on right in Lawyer's Building. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.124; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Rear of Durham Life Insurance Building c. 1947. Rear of the Durham Life Insurance building is seen from the intersection of Davie and Salisbury Streets in Raleigh, NC. An Esso station is seen on the corner, cars are seen parked on the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1947, PhC.68.1.125; Carolina Power and Light
- Henderson, NC, Elevated View of 200 block of Garnett Street Looking Northeast c.1915 (Formerly mis-identified as Wilmington Street, Raleigh, NC). 200 block of Garnett Street, Henderson, NC, looking northeast. Fire Station with tower is at the end of the street in background. This photo was previously mis-identified as "Wilmington St. business district, looking south, elevated view, ca. 1915, Raleigh, NC. Overall Elevated Street Scene View of Part of the Wilmington Street Business District, Looking South, at Raleigh, Wake County, North Carolina; Photograph Taken circa 1915.", PhC.68.1.126; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, 200 Block of South Wilmington Street c. 1903. 200 Block of Wilmington Street looking south. The back side of City Market is seen on extreme right. Photo taken at the intersection of Wilmington and Exchange Street (Plaza). Horse drawn carriages hauling goods, people walking and standing in unpaved street and various shops and businesses are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1903, PhC.68.1.127; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Intersection of Wilmington and Hargett Streets c.1923. Wilmington Street at the intersection of Hargett Street looking north in Raleigh, North Carolina. Automobiles and various businesses are seen lining the street. Businesses include Federal Clothing Company, M. Rosenthal and Company, Lewis Sporting Goods, Wood's Place and others. A very early traffic light is seen clearly at the intersection. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1923, PhC.68.1.128; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, 300 Block South Wilmington Street c. 1926. 300 block of south Wilmington Street in Raleigh, NC is seen. Various businesses are seen including, People's Lunch, Alderman and Co., Holeman Produce Co. and others. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.129; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Wilmington Street Looking South From Morgan Street c. 1927. Wilmington Street in Raleigh, NC looking south. First Baptist Church can be seen on left. Various businesses can be seen on the left side of the street along with parked automobiles. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1927, PhC.68.1.130; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Wilmington Street Looking North c. 1943. South Wilmington Street looking north in Raleigh, NC. Automobiles, pedestrians and businesses including Hudson Belk, Job P. Wyatt and Sons, and Citizens bank and others are seen lining the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1943, PhC.68.1.131; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking South From Morgan Street c. 1917. Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC looking south from Morgan Street at night. Streetlights can be seen lighting the buildings and roadway along Fayetteville. Print caption reads, "Form 10 Ornamental Luminous Arc Lamp Mounted on Bracket". No cars or pedestrians seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1917, PhC.68.1.132.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking North from Davie Street c. 1917., PhC.68.1.133.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated Night View of Fayetteville Street From NC Capitol c.1924. Elevated view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC at night. Photograph taken from NC Capitol Dome looking south. Streetlights are seen lighting up the buildings and roadway. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1924, PhC.68.1.134.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of Fayetteville Street Looking South c. 1924. Fayetteville Street looking south from Morgan Street in Raleigh, NC at night. Streetcar rails are seen running into the distance. The streets and buildings are seen illuminated by streetlights. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1924, PhC.68.1.135; Carolina Power and Light